<resources>
    <string name="app_name">INDIA</string>
    <string name="article_title" ><b><font size = "30">ABOUT INDIA\n</font></b></string>

    <string name="article_description"><font size = "17">\nIndia, also known as the Republic of India,
        is a country in South Asia. It is the seventh-largest country by area, the second-most populous country
        (with over 1,200 crore (1.2 billion) people), and the most populous democracy in the world.
        Bounded by the Indian Ocean on the south, the Arabian Sea on the southwest, and the Bay of Bengal on the
        southeast, it shares land borders with Pakistan to the west; China, Nepal, and Bhutan to the northeast;
        and Bangladesh and Myanmar to the east. In the Indian Ocean, India is in the vicinity of Sri Lanka and the Maldives,
        while its Andaman and Nicobar Islands share a maritime border with Thailand and Indonesia.</font></string>

    <string name="describe_states"><b>\nIndia is a federal union comprising 29 states and 7 union territories, for a total of 36
        entities. The states and union territories are further subdivided into districts and smaller administrative divisions.\n</b></string>

    <string name="describe_union"><b>\nA union territory is a type of administrative division in the Republic of India.
        Unlike the states of India, which have their own governments, union territories are federal territories ruled
        directly by the union government (central government), hence the name "union territory".\n</b></string>

    <string name="under"><u>Seven Union Territories</u>\n</string>

    <string name="describe_union1">Chandigarh is one of the best city in India, it is also known as The Green city of India.
        Chandigarh, is the capital of state Haryana and Punjab. It is considered as the first well planned city of India.
        Rock Garden and sukhna lake are good places to visit, a bird sanctuary is also located in the city which is home for a
        variety of bird species.\n</string>

    <string name="describe_union2">Dadra and Nagar Haveli located between Maharashtra and Gujarat and few kilometers from
        the city of Daman. A beautiful lake Garden Vanganga is located at the entrance of the city. Because of its scenic
        natural beauty and pleasant climate, Dadra and Nagar Haveli are dream tourist destinations.
        Silvassa the capital is one of the best place to visit.\n</string>

    <string name="describe_union3">Daman and Diu is located on western coast of India, Daman city is the capital having an area of
        72km. Daman and Diu is the second smallest among the other union territories in India. It has a mix culture of Indian
        and Portuguese. Daman and Diu is known for its untouched and explorer natural beauty. A trip to the famous beaches,
        Portuguese churches and forts of Daman and Diu can not be forgettable.\n</string>

    <string name="describe_union4">Lakshadweep is the smallest union territories in terms of area as well as in population.
        Lakshadweep located off of the coast of Kerala in the Laccadive Sea. The total area is 32 km and Kavaratti is the
        capital with a largest city is Andrott. Lakshadweep is fast becoming India’s one of the best tourism location for its
        kinds “Adventure sports”. Some of the Island’s are still inhabited and full of natural beauty.\n</string>

    <string name="describe_union5">Pondicherry is located on the eastern ghat of India. It was a former French colony.
        Puducherry is one of the most popular tourist destinations in South India. Beaches and Churches in Puducherry are
        most popular tourist attraction. It is also one of the educational hubs in southern India.\n</string>

    <string name="describe_union6">Andaman and Nicobar are the group of island located in the Indian Ocean.
        The Andamans and Nicobars are separated by a channel. These Islands are blessed with a unique tropical evergreen forest.
        The British used this islands as an isolated prison know as “Kala pani” for Indian freedom fighters. Local people of Islands
        still maintained their separated existence, these Indian Tribes are known as Jarwa and Great Andamanese.
        Port Blair is the largest city and the capital of Island.\n</string>

    <string name="describe_union7">The official name National Capital Territory of Delhi, in 1956 Delhi was converted into
        a Union territory. Delhi is a largest metro green city by area in India and eighth in the world by population.
        Delhi also own NationalCapital Region urban area in which Noida, Gurgaon, Greater Noida, Faridabad and Ghaziabad
        are included.\n</string>
    
    <string name="describe_river"><b>The rivers of India play an important role in the lives of the Indians.
        They provide potable water, cheap transportation, electricity, and the livelihood for a large number of people all
        over the country. This easily explains why nearly all the major cities of India are located by the banks of rivers.
        The rivers also have an important role in Hindu Religion and are considered holy by all Hindus in the country.\n</b></string>

    <string name="describe_port"><b>India has a coastline spanning 7516.6 kilometres, forming one of the biggest peninsulas in the world.
        According to the Ministry of Shipping, around 95 per cent of India s trading by volume and 70 per cent by value is done
        through maritime transport. It is serviced by 12 major ports, 200 notified minor and intermediate ports. The total 200
        non-major ports are in the following States:- Maharashtra (48); Gujarat (42); Tamil Nadu (15); Karnataka (10); Kerala (17);
        Andhra Pradesh (12); Odisha (13); Goa (5); West Bengal (1); Daman and Diu (2); Lakshadweep (10); Pondicherry (2); and
        Andaman and Nicobar (23).\n</b></string>

    <string name="seaports"><u>Twelve Major Sea Ports\n</u></string>

    <string name="describe_kandla">Gujarat host the major seaport of west coast, The Kandla Port is situated on
        the Gulf of Kutch near the Gandhidham city in Kutch District of Gujarat. The Port of Kandla is the first special
        economic zone in India as well as in Asia. Kandla Port is hub for major imports like petroleum, chemicals and iron also
        export grains, salt and textiles. Port of Kandla is one of the highest earning ports of India, another port in Gujarat
        is Mundra Port,India’s largest private port.\n</string>

    <string name="describe_nhava_sheva">Nhava Sheva now known as Jawaharlal Nehru Port is the largest container port in India,
        situated at the mainland of Konkan area across the Navi Mumbai Maharashtra. Jawaharlal Nehru Port is the king port of
        Arabian Sea at west cost and handle a large volume of international container traffic and domestic cargo traffic.
        The major exports are textiles, carpets, boneless meat and main imports are machinery,vegetable oils and chemicals.\n</string>

    <string name="describe_mumbai">The Mumbai Port is located in the mainland of west Mumbai on the West coast of India with
        natural deep-water harbor. Mumbai Port is the largest port in India and handles bulk cargo traffic with its four jetties
        for handling Liquid chemicals, Crude and petroleum products. International container traffic of Mumbai Port is directed
        to the new and big Nhava Sheva port.\n</string>

    <string name="describe_marmagao">"The main port of Goa, Marmagao port is a best natural harbors of India located in South Goa. Marmagao port
        is one of the leading iron ores exporter port in India and raw materials too.The port of Marmagao is one of the major attraction of Goa
        along with the beautiful city of Vasco da Gama and international airport Dabolim. The natural harbor of Goa is one of India’s earliest
        modern ports.\n</string>

    <string name="describe_panambur">Panambur Port known as the New Mangalore Port, is a seaport located near to Surathkal
        railway station in Dakshina Kannada district of Karnataka. New Mangalore Port is a deep water all weather port and the
        only major port of Karnataka and one of the largest port in India. Port of Mangalore export major commodities like
        manganese, granite stones, coffee and cashew and main imports includes timber logs, LPG, petroleum products and cargo
        containers. There is a beautiful beach at south of sea port of Panambur along with the shore of the Arabian Sea.\n</string>

    <string name="describe_cochin">The Cochin port is one of the largest port in India and the major
        port on the Arabian Sea and Indian Ocean sea route. The port of Cochin lies on two islands of Willingdon and
        Vallarpadam and the largest container transshipment facility in India. Kochi Port is equipped with maritime facilities
        Cochin Shipyard,Kochi Refineries and Kochi Marina. Kochi city is famous for its traditional spices and well known as \
        the port city of Fort Kochi during the European colonials. It also get its individual Kochi international airport,
        third international airport in the state of Kerala.\n</string>

    <string name="describe_port_blair">Port Blair is the capital city of Andaman Nicobar Islands, a Union Territory of India
        located at the juncture of the Bay of Bengal and Andaman Sea. Port Blair is the youngest sea port in India and one of the
        12 major port of the country. The only port of Andaman islands are connected to mainland of India through flight and ship.
        Port Blair is the principal hub for shipping in the islands of Andaman and the one of the most popular tourist destination
        with several places of interest around like virgin beaches, scuba diving and water sports.\n</string>

    <string name="describe_tuticorin">b>Tuticorin Port is an artificial deep-sea harbour and one of the 12 major ports of India.
        It is also the second largest port in Tamil Nadu first is Chennai Port and one of the largest container terminal in India.
        The artificial port of Tuticorin is a all weather port and who receive a large volume of international traffic. Port of
        Tuticorin are a used to be best port for maritime trade and pearl fishery on the bay of Bengal. The port city is also
        known as Pearl City and is one of the beautiful sea gateways of India from Tamil Nadu state.\n</string>

    <string name="describe_chennai">Madras Port is the one of the oldest port of India and the second largest port in the
        country. Chennai Port also the largest port in the Bay of Bengal and a hub port for cars, big containers and cargo
        traffic in the east coast of India. Port of the Coromandel Coast handles a variety of cargo containers, automobiles,
        coal,fertilizers and petroleum products. Chennai Port terminals have lighthouses around,Intra port connectivity,
        Pipelines and railway terminus.\n</string>
    
    <string name="describe_vizag">The port city Visakhapatnam is located on the southeast coast of India in the state of
        Andhra Pradesh. Visakhapatnam or Vizag has one of the India’s largest seaport and the oldest shipyard of country.
        The Visakhapatnam harbors is the only Natural harbors in the bay of Bengal shore. Kakinada Port is second port city in
        Andhra and Krishnapatnam Port is a privately built deep water port in Andhra Pradesh.\n</string>

    <string name="describe_paradip">The artificial, deep-water port of east coast of India is located in the Jagatsinghpur
        district of Orissa state. Port of Paradip is the major port in the east cost shore and situated at the confluence of great
        river Mahanadi and the Bay of Bengal. Paradip Port has its own railway system,cold handling plant and a national highway
        connects the port with rest of Indian road networks.\n</string>

    <string name="describe_haldia">Haldia port or Calcutta Port is a major seaport situated near the Hooghly River in the state of
        West Bengal. Port of Haldia is one of the major trade center for Calcutta and receive bulk cargoes of Chemicals,
        Petrochemicals and oils. Port of Kolkata is also a base of Indian Coast Guard.\n</string>


</resources>
